Guide to the A. Sidney Lovett Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
A. Sidney Lovett papers
1889-1979
MS 1089
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
29.25
(79 boxes)
Correspondence, sermons, writings, photographs, printed material and miscellanea detailing the professional career and personal life of Sidney Lovett, a clergyman and chaplain at Yale University. Lovett's activities as a minister in Boston (1919-1932), chaplain at Yale (1932-1958), member of many university organizations and committees, including the Yale Faculty Committee for Receiving Oxford and Cambridge Children and Yale-in-China, pastor of the Church of Christ in Yale, master of Pierson College, community worker in New Haven, Connecticut and professor of biblical literature, are documented in the papers. General correspondence files contain letters to and from Lovett, and include exchanges with numerous religious figures in academic positions, Yale University officials and employees, and Yale students and alumni. Correspondence and other materials relating to the Yale Faculty Committee for Receiving Oxford and Cambridge Children detail the efforts of that body to transport British children to the United States during World War II. Yale-in-China files detail Lovett's role as executive vice-president of that body. Sermons include printed and manuscript versions of many of Lovett's religious addresses, from 1914-1977, and writings include various other addresses, essays, funeral services and speeches.
Lovett, Sidney, 1890-1979
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research. Box 37, student gradebooks (1939-1949) are restricted until January 1, 2024 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Richard and Sidney Lovett, and Eugenia West Lovett, 1981-1983.
Arrangement
Arranged in five series: I. General Correspondence, 1889-1979. II. Yale Faculty Committee for Receiving Oxford and Cambridge Children, 1940-1948. III. Yale-in-China, 1933-1979. IV. Sermons, 1914-1977. V. Writings and Miscellanea, 1900-1979.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, sermons, writings, photographs, printed material and miscellanea detailing the professional career and personal life of Sidney Lovett, a clergyman and chaplain at Yale University. Lovett's activities as a minister in Boston (1919-1932), chaplain at Yale (1932-1958), member of many university organizations and committees, including the Yale Faculty Committee for Receiving Oxford and Cambridge Children and Yale-in-China, pastor of the Church of Christ in Yale, master of Pierson college, community worker in New Haven, Connecticut, and professor of biblical literature, are documented in the papers. General correspondence files contain letters to and from Lovett, and include exchanges with numerous religious figures in academic positions, Yale University officials and employees, and Yale students and alumni. Correspondence and other materials relating to the Yale Faculty Committee for Receiving Oxford and Cambridge Children detail the efforts of that body to transport British children to the United States during World War II. Yale-in-China files detail Lovett's role as executive vice-president of that body. Sermons include printed and manuscript versions of many of Lovett's religious addresses, from 1914-1977, and writings include various other addresses, essays, funeral services and speeches.
The Lovett Papers are arranged in 79 boxes, totalling 29.25 linear feet, The papers are organized in five series: I. CORRESPONDENCE, 1889-1979; II. YALE FACULTY COMMITTEE FOR RECEIVING OXFORD AND CAMBRIDGE CHILDREN, 1940-1948; III. YALE-IN-CHINA, 1933-1979; IV. SERMONS, 1914-1937; V. WRITINGS AND MISCELLANEA, 1900-1979. The Lovett Papers were donated by Richard and Sidney Lovett, and Eugenia West Lovett, from 1981-1983.
SERIES I, CORRESPONDENCE, 1889-1979, contains Lovett's personal and professional correspondence. His extensive role in the religious and academic operations of Yale University is documented through letters to and from James Rowland Angell, Henry Sloane Coffin, Alfred Whitney Griswold, Carl Albert Lohman, Elmore McNeil McKee, Charles Seymour, Norman Sydney Buck, Irving S. Fisher, Chauncey W. Goodrich, Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis, Addison Grant Noble, Richard Carter Nyman, and many others. Many letters with Yale University students and alumni, frequently addressed to "Uncle Sid," are also arranged in this series. Correspondence relating to such university organizations and topics as the Battell Chapel Memorial Fund, Berkeley Association, Church of Christ in Yale University, Dwight Hall, Pierson College, the academic courses "Religion 21" and "Religion 22," the religious affiliations of students, university preaching schedules, the Yale Alumni Fund, and the Yale University Christian Mission are organized in this series.
Sidney Lovett's activities outside the Yale University community include membership and participation in several New Haven area organizations as well as many influential national organizations. Correspondence detailing his contributions to the Abbott Academy (Andover, Mass.), Austin Riggs Foundation, Family Service of New Haven, the Fellowship of Reconciliation, George Junior Republic Association, Hopkins Grammar School, Interfaith Education Council, the New Haven Commission on Equal Opportunities, the Ulysses S. Grant Foundation, and the World Student Service Fund, is organized in this series. Correspondence with many religious figures, university and college chaplains, and family members are also arranged here.
SERIES II, YALE FACULTY COMMITTEE FOR RECEIVING OXFORD AND CAMBRIDGE CHILDREN, 1940-1948, contains correspondence and other material detailing Lovett's service as chairman, of this organization. The organizational and logistical problems of transferring the young children of oxford and Cambridge University faculty members to the United States during World War II, and the participation of the Yale University community in this effort, are documented.
SERIES III, YALE-IN-CHINA, 1933-1979, contains correspondence and material relating to Lovett's service as executive vice-president of this organization, now known as Yale-China Association. Lovett's correspondence is supplemented by printed material and reports.
SERIES IV, SERMONS, 1914-1977, contains many items Lovett prepared as minister of the Mount Vernon Congregational Church (Boston, Mass.), from 1920-1932; for the Northfield League, 1924-1925; as chaplain of Yale University, 1932-1977; and for other occassions, 1914-1972. These sermons include printed and manuscript versions, and focus on a wide range of religious topics.
SERIES V, WRITINGS AND MISCELLANEA, 1900-1979, contains several types of material, including writings, photographs, printed material, memorabilia, and audio tapes and films. Lovett's writings include short addresses prepared for baccalaureate services, commencement services, and prayers. Additional writings include essays, lectures, notebooks, and speeches.
Biographical / Historical
Augustus Sidney Lovett, Jr. was born in Boston, Massachusetts in 1890. He received his B.A. degree from Yale in 1913, and the B.D. degree from Union Theological Seminary in New York in 1917. From 1919-1932, Lovett served as minister of the Mount Vernon Congregational Church in Boston. In 1932 he was appointed chaplain of Yale University, a position he held until retirement in 1958. Lovett was appointed executive vice-president of Yale-in-China, now known as Yale-China, in 1959. He died in New Haven, Connecticut, on April 3, 1979.
College chaplains; Religion -- Study and teaching; World War, 1939-1945; New Haven (Conn.); Sermons; Clergy; Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949; Bayne-Jones, Stanhope, 1888-1970; Bryan, Robert A., 1926-; Buck, Norman Sydney, 1892-1964; Budlong, Frederick G., 1881-1953; Campbell, Edward F., Jr. (Edward Fay), 1932-; Chipman, Reeve; Coffin, Henry Sloane, 1877-1954; Coffin, William Sloane, Jr., 1924-2006; DeVane, William C. (William Clyde), 1898-1965; Fisher, Irving, 1867-1947; Fosdick, Harry Emerson, 1878-1969; Fry, Clements Collard, 1892-1955; Goodrich, Chauncey W.; Griswold, Alfred Whitney, 1906-1963; Hilgendorf, Howard W.; Hutchins, Francis S. (Francis Stephenson), 1902-; Lee, Richard C. (Richard Charles), 1916-2003; Lewis, W. S. (Wilmarth Sheldon), 1895-1979; Lohmann, Carl A. (Carl Albert), 1887-; Lovett, Sidney, 1890-1979; McKee, Elmore McNeill, 1896-; Noble, Addison Grant; Nyman, Richmond Carter, 1900-; Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963; Lovett family; Abbot Academy; Austin Riggs Foundation; Battell Chapel Memorial Fund; Betsy Ross Nursery School (New Haven, Conn.); B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundations; Committee on the Allocation of Students to the Colleges; Connecticut Prison Association; Dwight Hall (Yale University); Fellowship of Reconciliation (U.S.); George Junior Republic Association; Hopkins Grammar School; Hsin Ya shu yüan (Knowloon, Hong Kong); Inter-faith Education Council; International Migration Service; International Social Service; Mt. Vernon Congregational Church (Boston, Mass.); National Association of College and University Chaplains; National Conference of Chaplains; National Japanese American Student Relocation Council; New England Grenfell Association; Pierson College (Yale University); Salisbury School; Student Christian Movement in New England; Ulysses S. Grant Foundation; University Christian Council; Yale Alumni Fund; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1913; Yale Faculty Committee for Receiving Oxford and Cambridge University Children; Yale Hope Mission (New Haven, Conn.); Yale University -- Chaplains; Yale University -- Officals and employees; Yale University -- Religion; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Berkeley Association; Yale College (1718-1887). Church of Christ; Yale University. Treasurer; Yale-China Association
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1889-1979; Series I; 20; (52 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence arranged in alphabetical order by the individual correspondent, organization, or topic. Miscellaneous files, boxes 50-52, are arranged in chronological order.
  - A (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Abbott Academy, 1932-1948 (Box 1, Folder 5-8)
  - Addresses, 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Angell, James Rowland, 1931-1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Army, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Austin Riggs Foundation, 1942-1946 (Box 2, Folder 12-16)
  - B (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - B (Box 3, Folder 19-21)
  - Battell Chapel Memorial Fund, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 22-26)
  - Berkeley Association, 1939-1943 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Betsy Ross Nursery School, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Biographical Material, 1932, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Birth Control, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Budgets, 1939-1948 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Bulletins, 1940-1942 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - C (Box 4, Folder 33-35)
  - C (Box 5, Folder 36-37)
  - Chapel Committee, 1931-1933 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Chaplains, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Chipman, Reeve, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Choir, 1939-1944 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Choir gowns, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Church of Christ in Yale University
    - General, 1930, 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 43-45)
    - Annual meetings, 1940-1959 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Clerk's files, 1923-1930 (Box 6, Folder 47-49)
    - Members, 1931-1948 (Box 6, Folder 50-54)
    - Members, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Parish meetings, 1930-1949 (Box 7, Folder 56-57)
    - Reports to the President, 1928-1959 (Box 7, Folder 58-60)
    - Treasurer's files, 1923-1930 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Circular letters, 1932-1948 (Box 8, Folder 62-63)
  - Civilian defense, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Class of 1913, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Class of 1954, undated (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Coffin, Henry Sloane, 1939-1943 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Coffin, William Sloane, Jr., 1964-1970 (Box 8, Folder 68-69)
  - Committee on the Allocation of Students…, 1941-1942 (Box 8, Folder 70-71)
  - D (Box 9, Folder 72-73)
  - Daily Chapel, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Danbury, Ct., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Deacons, 1939-1949 (Box 9, Folder 76-79)
  - Dwight Hall, 1935-1937 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Dwight Hall, 1939-1949; 1964-1969 (Box 10, Folder 81-86)
  - E (Box 10, Folder 86-88)
  - Episcopalians, 1932-1955 (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - F (Box 11, Folder 90-94)
  - Family Service of New Haven, 1947-1949 (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - Fan mail, 1939-1942 (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Fellowship of Reconcilliation, 1939-1940 (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Flowers, 1940-1946 (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - Freshman class, 1934; 1939-1946 (Box 12, Folder 99-100)
  - G (Box 12, Folder 101-107)
  - George Junior Republic Association, 1940-1948 (Box 13, Folder 108-109)
  - H (Box 13, Folder 110-117)
  - Hillel Foundation, 1964-1966 (Box 14, Folder 118)
  - Hopkins Grammar School, 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 119)
  - Hymn book, 1930; 1953-1955 (Box 14, Folder 120-125)
  - I (Box 14, Folder 126)
  - Interfaith Education Council, 1940-1944 (Box 14, Folder 127)
  - Interfaith Education Council, 1945-1949 (Box 15, Folder 128)
  - International Social Services, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 129)
  - J (Box 15, Folder 130-131)
  - K (Box 15, Folder 132-133)
  - L (Box 15, Folder 134-137)
  - Lohman, Carl A., 1926-1948 (Box 15, Folder 138-139)
  - Lovett, A. Sidney, Jr.
    - Select
      - Lovett, A. Sidney, Sr., 1896-1926 (Box 16, Folder 140)
      - Lovett, Elizabeth R., 1889-1909 (Box 16, Folder 141-148)
      - Lovett, Elizabeth R., 1910-1912 (Box 17, Folder 149-151)
      - Lovett, Elizabeth R., 1913-1915 (Box 18, Folder 152-154)
      - Lovett, Elizabeth R., 1916-1917 (Box 19, Folder 155-157)
      - Lovett, Elizabeth R., 1919-1921, undated (Box 20, Folder 158-160)
      - Lovett, Rebekah Mills, undated (Box 20, Folder 164)
    - Personal, 1939-1948, undated (Box 21, Folder 165-172)
    - General, 1902-1948 (Box 22, Folder 173-190)
  - Lovett family, 1904-1920 (Box 23, Folder 191-196)
  - M (Box 24, Folder 197-202)
  - McKee, Elmore, 1929-1930 (Box 24, Folder 203-205)
  - McKee, Elmore, 1929-1930 (Box 25, Folder 206-208)
  - Mental Hygiene, 1940 (Box 25, Folder 209)
  - Miscellaneous, 1940-1949 (Box 25, Folder 210-213)
  - Missions, 1964-1968 (Box 25, Folder 214)
  - N (Box 25, Folder 215-218)
  - National Association of College and University Chaplains, 1951-1952 (Box 26, Folder 219)
  - National Committee on Food for the Five Small Democracies, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 220)
  - National Conference of Chaplains, 1948-1949 (Box 26, Folder 221)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1935-1936 (Box 26, Folder 223)
  - National Japanese Student Relocation Council, 1943-1945 (Box 26, Folder 224)
  - National Prepatory School Committee, 1938-1939 (Box 26, Folder 225)
  - Negro colleges, 1945-1947 (Box 26, Folder 226)
  - New England Grenfell Association, 1940-1947 (Box 26, Folder 227)
  - New England Student Christian Movement, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 228)
  - New Haven Association of Congregational Churches and Ministers, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 229)
  - New Haven Boys Club, 1940-1942 (Box 26, Folder 230)
  - New Haven Chapter/American Association for the United Nations, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 231)
  - New Haven Commission on Equal Opportunities, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 232)
  - New Haven Commission on Equal Opportunities, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 233)
  - New Haven Council of Churches, 1948-1949 (Box 26, Folder 234)
  - Noble, Addison E., 1939-1940 (Box 27, Folder 235)
  - Nyman, R. Carter, 1940-1948 (Box 27, Folder 236-227)
  - O (Box 27, Folder 238-239)
  - Overseas Educational Service, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 240)
  - P (Box 27, Folder 241-246)
  - Peace, 1939-1946 (Box 28, Folder 247)
  - Perry, Mary G., 1938-1939 (Box 28, Folder 248)
  - Pew seats, 1933-1941 (Box 28, Folder 249-250)
  - Pierson College, 1953-1954 (Box 28, Folder 251-252)
  - Pledges, 1952-1953 (Box 28, Folder 253-254)
  - Prayers, 1936-1947 (Box 28, Folder 255)
  - Q (Box 28, Folder 256)
  - R (Box 29, Folder 257-262)
  - Recommendations
    - General, 1962-1967 (Box 29, Folder 263-268)
    - General, 1968-1972 (Box 30, Folder 269-270)
    - Emory, Linden, 1965-1969 (Box 30, Folder 271)
    - Jones, Douglas C., 1965-1966 (Box 30, Folder 272)
    - King, Stephen, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 273)
  - Recording for the Blind, 1964-1969 (Box 30, Folder 274)
  - Religion 21 and 22, 1943-1954 (Box 30, Folder 275-278)
  - Religious affiliations
    - General, 1929-1936 (Box 30, Folder 279-281)
    - General, 1937-1951 (Box 31, Folder 282-293)
    - General, 1952-1958 (Box 32, Folder 294-298)
    - Graduate students, 1929-1935 (Box 32, Folder 299)
    - Jewish students, 1933-1946 (Box 32, Folder 300)
  - Religious studies group, 1943 (Box 32, Folder 301)
  - Report of the Committee on the Course of Study to the General Faculty of Yale College, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 302)
  - Report of the President's Committee on General Education, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 303)
  - S (Box 32, Folder 304-306)
  - S (Box 33, Folder 307-314)
  - Saint Paul's School, 1943-1945 (Box 33, Folder 315)
  - Salisbury School (Box 33, Folder 316-318)
  - Savitt, Robert, 1968-1969 (Box 34, Folder 319)
  - Seymour, Charles, 1938-1949 (Box 34, Folder 320-322)
  - Social Action Committee, 1933-1941 (Box 34, Folder 323-324)
  - Social agencies, 1942 (Box 34, Folder 323)
  - Speaking engagements, 1964-1971 (Box 34, Folder 324-327)
  - Student Christian Movement in New England, 1938-1939 (Box 34, Folder 328)
  - Students, 1931-1935 (Box 34, Folder 329-330)
  - Students, 1935-1943 (Box 35, Folder 331-338)
  - Students, 1946-1954 (Box 36, Folder 339-347)
  - Students: grade books, 1939-1949 (Box 37, Folder 348-353)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Material is restricted until January 1, 2024 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Sunday School, 1931-1947 (Box 38, Folder 354-355)
  - T (Box 38, Folder 356-359)
  - Tercentenary service, 1935 (Box 38, Folder 360)
  - Treasurer's Office
    - Correspondence, 1932-1939 (Box 38, Folder 361-362)
    - Correspondence, 1940- (Box 39, Folder 363-369)
    - Reports (Box 39, Folder 370-331)
  - U (Box 40, Folder 372)
  - Ulysses S. Grant Foundation, 1965-1978 (Box 40, Folder 373-374)
  - United Board of Christian Higher Education, 1968-1969 (Box 40, Folder 375)
  - United World Federalists, 1967-1968 (Box 40, Folder 376)
  - University Christian Council, 1966 (Box 40, Folder 377)
  - University Christian Movement, 1963-1964 (Box 40, Folder 378)
  - University preachers, 1930-1940 (Box 40, Folder 379-382)
  - University preachers, 1940-1944 (Box 41, Folder 383-388)
  - University preachers, 1944-1947 (Box 42, Folder 389-394)
  - University preachers, 1947-1955 (Box 43, Folder 395-400)
  - University preachers, 1953-1955 (Box 44, Folder 401-402)
  - University preaching mission, 1939-1940 (Box 44, Folder 403)
  - V (Box 44, Folder 404-406)
  - Vespers, 1939-1948 (Box 44, Folder 407)
  - W (Box 44, Folder 408)
  - W (Box 45, Folder 409-412)
  - Weigle, Luther, 1940 (Box 45, Folder 413)
  - World Student Service Fund, 1939-1941 (Box 45, Folder 414-415)
  - World War II, 1941-1945 (Box 46, Folder 416-421)
  - World War II, 1941-1945 (Box 47, Folder 422-424)
  - Y (Box 47, Folder 425-429)
  - Yale Alumni Fund, 1961-1976 (Box 47, Folder 430-435)
  - Yale Hope Mission, 1941-1946; 1963 (Box 48, Folder 436-438)
  - Yale Medal, 1974-1977 (Box 48, Folder 439)
  - Yale University Christian Association, 1937-1939 (Box 48, Folder 440)
  - Yale University Christian Conference, 1939-1947 (Box 49, Folder 441-445)
  - Yale University Christian Mission, 1949-1952 (Box 49, Folder 446-449)
  - Yale University Committee on the Presidency, 1963 (Box 49, Folder 450)
  - Z (Box 49, Folder 451)
  - Miscellaneous, 1912-1973 (Box 50, Folder 452-481)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974-1978 (Box 51, Folder 482-493)
  - Miscellaneous, 1979, undated (Box 52, Folder 494-506)
- YALE FACULTY COMMITTEE FOR RECEIVING OXFORD AND CAMBRIDGE CHILDREN, 1940-1948; Series II; 2 linear feet (5 boxes)
  This series contains correspondence and other material arranged alphabetically by the type of material and/or the topic. General correspondence files, however, are arranged at the beginning of the series.
  - General correspondence, 1940-1948 (Box 53, Folder 507-514)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1940 (Box 53, Folder 515)
  - Camps, 1940-1944 (Box 54, Folder 516-518)
  - Committee on Enrollment and Scholarship, 1945 (Box 54, Folder 519-520)
  - Committees: miscellaneous, 1945 (Box 54, Folder 521)
  - Forms, 1940-1944 (Box 54, Folder 522)
  - Minutes, 1940-1945 (Box 55, Folder 523-524)
  - Miscellanea (Box 55, Folder 525-527)
  - Oxford Party, 1940 (Box 55, Folder 528)
  - Oxford Summer School, 1948 (Box 55, Folder 529)
  - Oxford University Trust Fund
    - General, 1943-1949 (Box 56, Folder 530-532)
    - Evacuation Trust Fund, 1941-1947 (Box 56, Folder 533-534)
    - Philadelphia, 1940 (Box 56, Folder 535)
    - Placement Committee, 1941-1945 (Box 56, Folder 536-537)
    - Political pamphlets, 1949 (Box 56, Folder 538)
    - Publicity, 1940-1941 (Box 56, Folder 539)
    - Rhodes house, 1940 (Box 56, Folder 540)
    - Special forms, undated (Box 56, Folder 541)
    - Work camps, 1942 (Box 56, Folder 542)
  - Schools, 1941-1944 (Box 57, Folder 543-544)
  - 1945 trip (Box 57, Folder 545)
- YALE-IN-CHINA, 1933-1979; Series III; 1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
  This series contains correspondence and other material arranged alphabetically by type and/or topic.
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1933-1943 (Box 58, Folder 546-550)
    - General, 1943-1979 (Box 59, Folder 551-556)
    - Chinese, 1962-1967 (Box 59, Folder 557)
  - Far Eastern Conference Correspondence
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1964-1967 (Box 60, Folder 558-559)
      - Personal, 1959-1962 (Box 60, Folder 560)
    - Invitation lists, 1967 (Box 60, Folder 561)
    - Newsletters, 1967 (Box 60, Folder 562)
  - Kuo, Mimi, 1962-1965 (Box 60, Folder 563)
  - New Asia College, 1965 (Box 60, Folder 564)
  - Ng, Kam Yan, 1964-1969 (Box 60, Folder 565)
  - Park, Alphonse, 1967-1968 (Box 60, Folder 566)
  - Printed material, 1941-1975, undated (Box 60, Folder 567)
  - Reports, 1965 (Box 60, Folder 568)
- SERMONS, 1914-1977; Series IV; 3 linear feet (8 boxes)
  This series contains sermons delivered by Sidney Lovett from 1914-1977. The series is arranged in four sections: General, Mount Vernon Church, Northfield League, and Yale University. Each section is arranged chronologically.
  - General
    - 1914-1945 1914-1945 (Box 61, Folder 569-583)
    - 1946-1966 1946-1966 (Box 62, Folder 584-597)
    - 1967-1972, undated 1967-1972, undated (Box 63, Folder 598-610)
    - undated undated (Box 64, Folder 611-612)
  - Mount Vernon Church
    - 1920-1932, undated 1920-1932, undated (Box 65, Folder 613-622)
    - Northfield League, 1924-1925 1924-1925 (Box 66, Folder 623)
  - Yale University
    - Advent and Christmas, 1932-1941 (Box 66, Folder 624-628)
    - Holy Week, 1933-1941 (Box 66, Folder 629-631)
    - Holy Week, 1942-1977, undated (Box 67, Folder 632-638)
    - Miscellaneous, 1935-1975 (Box 67, Folder 639-642)
    - Miscellaneous, 1933-1971, undated (Box 68, Folder 643-655)
- WRITINGS AND MISCELLANEA, 1900-1979; Series V; 4 linear feet (11 boxes)
  This series is arranged in five sections: Writings, photographs, Printed material; Memorabilia, and Audio tapes and films.
  Each section is arranged alphabetically by type and/or topic.
  - Writings
    - Baccalaureate services, 1934-1970 (Box 69, Folder 656-657)
    - Commencement services, 1934-1958 (Box 69, Folder 658)
    - Dedication services, 1952; 1955 (Box 69, Folder 659)
    - Diaries, 1902-1917 (Box 69, Folder 660-661)
    - Essays, undated (Box 69, Folder 662-664)
    - Funeral services, 1936-1956 (Box 69, Folder 665)
    - Installation services, 1965-1966 (Box 69, Folder 666-667)
    - Lectures, undated (Box 69, Folder 668)